Joanne R. Peel

PhD Biological & Health Sciences Data Analyst/Statistician



(+52) 984 137 7678



peeljoanne@gmail.com



/joanne-peel



/JoannePeel

ABOUT ME -

I am data analyst who loves fish and cares about people's needs. I have accumulated more than 8 years of experience in the field of data collection, management, statistical analysis, demography and population analysis, which I would like to put to a good use for commercial purposes.

SKILLS

DESCRIPTIVE STATISTICS

INFERENTIAL STATISTICS

EXCEL (INCLUDING VBA + DATA ANALYSIS)

R (POPBIO, IPM, etc)

PYTHON (PANDAS, MATPLOTLIP, scipy.stats)

MICROSOFT OFFICE

GERMAN (native)

ENGLISH (TOEFL ITP 657=CI)

SPANISH (profesional efficiency)

Interests

Travel, Food & Drink, Friends & Family, Exercise

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Monterrey, CDMX — Data Science Bootcamp

November 2018 - May 2019

Advanced Excel, Python, JavaScript (D3.js, Leaflet.js), HTML5/CSS, API Interactions, Social Media Mining, SQL, Tableau, Advanced Statistics, Machine Learning, R, Git/GitHub, Big Data Analytics

Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, CDMX — PhD in Biological & Health Sciences

January 2014 - May 2018

High level research training in the field of biological and health sciences, through the realization of original research project: Fenology, demography and population dynamics of Rhizophora mangle.

CINVESTAV-IPN, Mérida, Yuc. — MsC in Marine Sciences

September 2010 - November 2012

Specialization in the field of marine biology, training in biostatistics and multivariate statistics (3 trimesters). Master thesis on original research project: Population dynamics of the Pink Queen Conch.

Universidad de Guadalajara, Guadalajara, Jal. — BsC in Biology

August 2004 - January 2010

Training in general biology and biostatistics (3 semesters).

Projects

Job satisfaction and emotional exhaustion as risk factors for job abandonment in medical residents — IMSS y Secretaría de Salud CDMX

June 2018 - August 2018

Medical residents are at high risk of suffering from depression and burnout, which can be linked to low job satisfaction, and may be an important factor leading to job abandonment.

My role: Design online survey, data collection, data analysis, data visualization, drafting of the report and publication.

Achievements: Participation in XV Foro Nacional e Internacional de Educación en Salud.

Phenology, demography and population dynamics of the red mangrove along a salinity gradient— *UAM-Xochimilco*

January 2014 - May 2018

Original research project on morphological and physiological response of mangroves to saline stress. My role. Research proposal, grant proposal, experimental design, data collection, data analysis, data visualization, drafting final report.

Achievements. PhD dissertation, I published article, I article in revision, participation in national congress.

Stomatal density and leave size of the red mangrove. — *UNAM*

February 2016 - November 2018

Original research project on morphological and physiological response of mangroves leaves to saline

My role. Thesis supervisor/advisor, grant proposal, supervising data collection, analysis and drafting process.

Achievements: BSc dissertation.

Joanne R. Peel

PhD Biological & Health Sciences
Data Analyst/Statistician

OTHER SKILLS

- Scientific writing
- Research
- Public speaking
- Training
- Project management

Certificates

Data Management for Clinical Research

Vanderbilt University (Coursera) May 2018 - July 2018

Critical concepts and practical methods to support planning, collection, storage, and dissemination of data in clinical research.

Good Clinical Practice — NIDA Clinical

Trial Network
May 2018

The Good Clinical Practice (GCP) course is designed to prepare research staff in the conduct of clinical trials with human participants, based on ICH GCP Principles and the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) for clinical research trials in the U.S.

Projects

Population dynamics and ontogenic habitat use of the pink queen conch— CINVESTAV, Mérida

September 2010 - November 2012

Original research project on the population dynamics, demography and age related habitat use of the pink queen conch.

My role: Research proposal, grant proposal, experimental design, data collection, data analysis, data visualization, drafting final report.

Achievements: MSc dissertation, 8 published articles, participation in international congresses.

Xel-Há, Pink Queen Conch Conservation— Xel-Há, Grupo Xcaret

January 2014 - May 2018

Long-term monitoring project of the pink queen conch in the Xel-Há Park.

My role. Intern, data collection, data base management, data analysis, data visualization, drafting periodical reports.

Achievements. Database containing 10 years of queen conch data.

BISTROM-Biology of the Strombus Maya — Institut Universitaire Européen de la Mer, James Cook University, CINVESTAV

June 2010 - June 2013

Original international research project on metabolism, habitat use, capacity as a bioarchive of the pink queen conch in the Xel-Há Park

My role. Intern, data collection, assisting field work and local logistics. Achievements. Publications and participation in international congress.

Job Experience

Self employed, CDMX — Property administrator

July 2018 — PRESENT

Overseeing the daily operations of the physical building, managing staff, budgets, subcontractors, negotiating leases and overseeing construction projects.

Xel-Há (Grupo Xcaret), Tulum, QR00 — Intern

June 2009 - May 2018

Managing and executing the Queen Conch (Strombus gigas) conservation and rehabilitation program, monitoring marine fauna and water quality, managing and analyzing data obtained from the monitoring programs, data visualization, drafting monthly reports.

IMSS-Centro de Investigación Biomédica del Occidente, Guadalajara, Jal. — Intern

January 20007 - December 2007 &

August 2003 - October 2003

Intern in the department for neuroscience (2007), immune biology (2003) and experimental surgery (2003).